<sentences><s id="0">Impact of <e id="UNIPROT:P11712:T116:PRGE">CYP2C9*3</e>, <e id="UNIPROT:Q9BQB6:T116:PRGE">VKORC1-1639</e>, CYP4F2rs2108622 genetic polymorphism and clinical factors on warfarin maintenance dose in Han-Chinese patients.</s>
<s id="1">To evaluate the impact of gene polymorphisms of <e id="UNIPROT:Q9HCS2:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P05177:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:Q8N1L4:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P13584:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P24462:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:Q7Z449:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P20815:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P20853:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P10635:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P04798:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:Q96SQ9:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P33261:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P20813:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:Q02928:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P11511:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:Q86W10:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:Q16696:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:Q6V0L0:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:Q9HBI6:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P24903:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P10632:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P51589:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:Q8N118:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P98187:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:Q16678:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P33260:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:Q9HB55:T116:PRGE">Cytochrome P450</e> 2C9 (<e id="UNIPROT:P11712:T116:PRGE">CYP2C9</e>), <e id="UNIPROT:Q9BQB6:T116:PRGE">Vitamin K epoxide reductase complex subunit 1</e> (<e id="UNIPROT:Q9BQB6:T116:PRGE">VKORC1</e>) and <e id="UNIPROT:P78329:T116:PRGE">Cytochrome P450 4F2</e> (<e id="UNIPROT:P78329:T116:PRGE">CYP4F2</e>) and clinical factors on warfarin maintenance dose in Han-Chinese patients from main land.</s> <s id="2">DNA was extracted from 115 patients taking warfarin for more than 3 months with a stable international normalized ratio (INR) and genotyped for <e id="UNIPROT:P11712:T116:PRGE">CYP2C9*3</e>, <e id="UNIPROT:Q9BQB6:T116:PRGE">VKORC1-1639</e> and <e id="UNIPROT:P78329:T116:PRGE">CYP4F2</e> (rs2108622) polymorphisms using polymerase chain reaction-restriction fragment length polymorphism (PCR-RFLP).</s> <s id="3">Univariate analysis and multiple regression analysis were undertaken to assess the effect of genetic and clinical factors on the warfarin maintenance dose.</s> <s id="4">Our study demonstrated that patients carrying <e id="UNIPROT:P78329:T116:PRGE">CYP4F2 CT</e> or TT allele needed a significantly higher warfarin dose compared to those carrying CC ((3.36 ± 0.14 mg/d vs. 2.77 ± 0.14 mg/d), P = 0.004).</s> <s id="5">We also confirmed <e id="UNIPROT:P11712:T116:PRGE">CYP2C9 *3</e> variant was related to lower warfarin dose (2.01 ± 0.23 mg/d) requirement compared to wild type (3.21 ± 0.11 mg/d) (P = 0.001).</s> <s id="6">VKORC1-1639 AG genotype was associated with a higher maintenance dose compared to those with the <e id="UMLS:C1862382:T047:DISO">AA</e> genotype (4.06 ± 0.21 mg/d vs. 2.95 ± 0.11 mg/d, P &lt; 0.001).</s> <s id="7">The multiple linear regression model including <e id="UNIPROT:Q9BQB6:T116:PRGE">VKORC1-1639G&gt;A</e>, <e id="UNIPROT:P11712:T116:PRGE">CYP2C9</e>, <e id="UNIPROT:P78329:T116:PRGE">CYP4F2</e> and clinical factors (body surface area (BSA) and age) could explain 42 % of the variance in the warfarin maintenance dose.</s> <s id="8">We developed a dose algorithm based on genetic polymorphism and clinical variables for Han-Chinese patients and evaluated its performance.</s> <s id="9"><e id="UNIPROT:P78329:T116:PRGE">CYP4F2</e> rs2108622 has a small but significant association with warfarin stable dose in Han-Chinese population.</s></sentences>