<sentences><s id="0"><e id="UNIPROT:Q8IZI9:T116:PRGE">IL28B</e> polymorphism is associated with treatment response in patients with genotype 4 <e id="UMLS:C0524910:T047:DISO">chronic hepatitis C</e>.</s>
<s id="1">Polymorphisms in the region of the <e id="UNIPROT:P60568:T116:PRGE">interleukin</e> (IL)28B gene have been associated with pegylated-<e id="UNIPROT:P01563:T116:PRGE|UNIPROT:P01569:T116:PRGE">interferon</e> (<e id="UNIPROT:P09466:T116:PRGE">PEG-IFN</e>) and ribavirin treatment response mainly in genotype 1 HCV <e id="UMLS:C0021311:T047:DISO|UMLS:C0851162:T047:DISO">infections</e>.</s> <s id="2">However, there are few data on HCV genotype 4 (HCV-4) <e id="UMLS:C0021311:T047:DISO|UMLS:C0009450:T047:DISO">infection</e>.</s> <s id="3">We evaluated, in a unique well-characterized cohort of HCV-4 patients, the association of <e id="UNIPROT:Q8IZI9:T116:PRGE">IL28B</e> polymorphism with response to treatment or <e id="(UMLS:C0023884:T023:ANAT):1|(UMLS:C0023895:T047:DISO):1,2"><w id="1">liver</w> <w id="2">disease</w></e> severity.</s>
<s id="4">This study included 164 HCV-4 patients from different ethnic groups (Egyptian, European, and Sub-Saharan African).</s> <s id="5">Among these patients, 82 were studied for response and 160 for disease severity.</s> <s id="6">Free DNA extracted from all the 164 patient&apos;s serum samples was analyzed by direct sequencing of the SNP rs12979860 of <e id="UNIPROT:Q8IZI9:T116:PRGE">IL28B</e>.</s> <s id="7">Genetic and bio-clinical features from patients having sustained virological response (43 SVR patients) and from those who did not respond to treatment or had a <e id="UMLS:C0277556:T047:DISO">relapse</e> after the end of the treatment (39 NR patients) were compared.</s> <s id="8"><e id="UNIPROT:Q8IZI9:T116:PRGE">IL28B</e> polymorphism was compared between the 78 patients with mild fibrosis (Metavir score F0-F1) and the 82 with advanced fibrosis (F2-F4).</s>
<s id="9">Our data showed a better treatment response rate of the C allele of the <e id="UNIPROT:Q8IZI9:T116:PRGE">IL28B gene SNP rs12979860</e> (p=0.0008).</s> <s id="10">The response rates were 81.8%, 46.5%, and 29.4% for genotype CC, CT, and TT, respectively.</s> <s id="11">No significant relationship was found between rs12979860 and the severity of the disease.</s>
<s id="12">The SNP rs12979860 is strongly associated with SVR in patients infected with HCV-4, but not with <e id="(UMLS:C0023884:T023:ANAT):1|(UMLS:C0023895:T047:DISO):1,2"><w id="1">liver</w> <w id="2">disease</w></e> severity.</s> <s id="13">Analysis of <e id="UNIPROT:Q8IZI9:T116:PRGE">IL28B genotype</e> might be used to guide treatment for these patients.</s></sentences>