<sentences><s id="0">A genome-wide association study identifies locus at 10q22 associated with clinical outcomes of adjuvant tamoxifen therapy for <e id="UMLS:C0006141:T023:ANAT">breast</e> cancer patients in Japanese.</s>
<s id="1">Although many association studies of polymorphisms in candidate genes with the clinical outcomes of <e id="UMLS:C0006141:T023:ANAT">breast</e> cancer patients receiving adjuvant tamoxifen therapy have been reported, genetic factors determining individual response to tamoxifen are not fully understood.</s> <s id="2">To identify genetic polymorphisms associated with clinical outcomes of patients with tamoxifen treatment, we conducted a genome-wide association study (GWAS).</s> <s id="3">We studied 462 Japanese patients with hormone receptor-positive, invasive <e id="UMLS:C0006141:T023:ANAT">breast</e> cancer receiving adjuvant tamoxifen therapy.</s> <s id="4">Of them, 240 patients were analyzed by genome-wide genotyping using the Illumina Human610-Quad BeadChips, and two independent sets of 105 and 117 cases were used for replication studies.</s> <s id="5">In the GWAS, we detected significant associations with recurrence-free survival at 15 single-nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) on nine chromosomal loci (1p31, 1q41, 5q33, 7p11, 10q22, 12q13, 13q22, 18q12 and 19p13) that satisfied a genome-wide significant threshold (log-rank P= 2.87 × 10(-9)-9.41 × 10(-8)).</s> <s id="6">Among them, rs10509373 in C10orf11 gene on 10q22 was significantly associated with recurrence-free survival in the replication study (log-rank P= 2.02 × 10(-4)) and a combined analysis indicated a strong association of this SNP with recurrence-free survival in <e id="UMLS:C0006141:T023:ANAT">breast</e> cancer patients treated with tamoxifen (log-rank P= 1.26 × 10(-10)).</s> <s id="7">Hazard ratio per C allele of rs10509373 was 4.51 [95% confidence interval (CI), 2.72-7.51; P= 6.29 × 10(-9)].</s> <s id="8">In a combined analysis of rs10509373 genotype with previously identified genetic makers, <e id="UNIPROT:P10635:T116:PRGE">CYP2D6</e> and <e id="UNIPROT:Q92887:T116:PRGE">ABCC2</e>, the number of risk alleles of these three genes had cumulative effects on recurrence-free survival among 345 patients receiving tamoxifen monotherapy (log-rank P= 2.28 × 10(-12)).</s> <s id="9">In conclusion, we identified a novel locus associated with recurrence-free survival in Japanese <e id="UMLS:C0006141:T023:ANAT">breast</e> cancer patients receiving adjuvant tamoxifen therapy.</s></sentences>